Leach, W. Barton (Walter Barton), 1900 -1971. Papers, 1920-1971: Finding Aid.
Papers, 1920-1971.
- CONTINGENT I
  - BIOGRAPHICAL AND OTHER MISCELLANY
    This Series contains clippings, photographs, correspondence, and typewritten drafts for a proposed autobiography (unpublished) by WBL. There is a good deal of material relating to his activities in the United States Air Force; also a section on legal poetry.
    The Series is arranged alphabetically.
    - Air Force-Advanced Degrees 3 folders, 48-7 to 48-9
      File relates to proposal to award Master's Degrees at the Air Force Academy.
    - Air Force- White, T homas D. (General) 3 folders, 48-10 to 48-12
      File contains correspondence dated 1952-1965. General White was Chief of Staff of the United States Air Force.
    - Anecdotes, 48-13
    - Autobiography: Drafts of Sections 5 folders, 48-14 to 49-2
      File contains copies of several drafts of different parts of WBL's projected work.
      49-2 is a looseleaf notebook.
    - Clippings, 49-3 to 49-7
      Clippings are about WBL, the Defense Policy Seminar and other subjects related to WBL's professional or military activities. All clippings had been intended for a scrapbook which was never assembled. Clippings have not been arranged in any kind of order. Clippings are mainly from the 1955-1957 period.
    - Clipping, correspondence (copy of letter from Erwin Griswold to Stuart Symington), article The Stupidity of a Big Navy by Leach., 49-7
    - Legal Poetry and Song 4 folders, 50-1 to 50-4
    - Photographs, 50-5
    - Miscellany 2 folders, 50-6 to 50-7
  - AIR FORCE
    Professor Leach's Air Force files consist chiefly of material relating to his service with the American Air Forces during World War II and subsequently with the United States Air Force, both active service and service after retirement. Files include his reports and memoranda relating to operations analysis; material relating to his work as a consultant; appointments and travel orders; correspondence concerning special missions; material relating to investigations of particular strategic weapons or aircraft; recommendations regarding the U.S. Air Force Academy at Colorado Springs and other Air Force schools.
    The Series contains a sizeable amount of correspondence with various staff officers. Among Professor Leach's major correspondents are: Harold Brown; James B. Conant; James H. Douglas, Jr.; Thomas K. Finletter; Murray Green; Henry A. Kissinger; Laurence S. Kuter; Curtis E. LeMay; Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr.; Glen W. Martin; Lauris Norstad; Thomas S. Power; Donald A. Quarles; Stuart Symington; Nathan P. Twining; Hoyt S. Vandenberg; Eugene M. Zuckert.
    All of this material is now de-classified (see letter in W.B. Leach, CASE FILE, at Curator's Desk).
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (alphabetical), 50-8 to 51-1
      - 50-8, Anderson, Fred L. 1946-1947 Alsop, Stewart 1951 Barcus, Glenn O. 1950 Beards, H.L. 1950 Beau, Lucas V. 1949 Belknap, J.H. 1950 Berry, Margaret 1949-1952 Billingslea, Charles 1950 Bowman, H.W. 1946 Brownell, Herbert, Jr. 1953 Carpenter, William E. 1946-1947 Cash, James L. 1951-1952 Combs, Cecil E. 1950
      - 50-9, Debeau, David E. 1950 Eaker, Ira C. 1950 Elliott, William Y. 1950 Everest, F.F. 1946-1951 Fairchild, Muir S. 1948 Fisher, William 1950 Gaston, Allen B. Gates, Byron E. 1947-1952 George, Harold L. 1946-1950 Hall, William 1950 Hamilton, Pierpont Morgan 1948-1950 Harlow, Bryce N. 1950 Hellmold, Heinz A.L. 1948 Hill, James C. 1951 Holmes, Ernest S., Jr. 1950 Hull, Harris B. 1947 Johnson, Leon W. 1950 Johnson, Patrick 1948 Jones, Harold L. 1950 Jones, Junius W. 1947 Kalberer, Alfred F. 1950 Kelly, Arthur F. 1952 Laird, Virginia 1950 Leo, Stephen 1948
      - 50-10, Leva, Marx 1948-1949 Lindsay, R.C. 1949 Lovett, Robert A. 1950 Low, Andrew 1949 Lynch, E.C. 1948 Lynch, Mary 1949 Lyons, Louis M. 1950 McIntyre, Judith 1947 McKee, William F. 1950 Matthews, Herbert L. 1951 Maxwell, Russell L. 1946 Meek, J.R.S. 1946 Miser, Hugh J. 1950 Montgomery, John B. 1947-1949 Morris, G.D. 1949 Murphy, Charles 1951 Myers, Charles T. 1950 Pace, Frank1951 Patterson, Robert 1950 Potts, Ramsay 1950-1952 Powell, L.J. 1952 Raudenbush, David W. 1948-1949 Sallagar, Frederick 1949-1952
      - 51-1, Scott, Philip C. 1949 Scott, Robert 1947 Shaw, Brackley 1949 Shearer, Douglas 1948 Smith, Sory 1949-1950 Stace, D.F. 1946 Stratemeyer, George E. 1947 Stroble, James 1949 Sundlun, B.G. 1948 Tanner, Van Holmgren 1948 Vanderbilt, Arthur T. 1946 Voorst, M. Van 1950 Wells, John H., Jr. 1949 White, Thomas D. 1946-1952
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (chronological), 51-2 to 51-6
      - Nov. 1, 1952 to Apr. 30, 1953, 51-2
      - Marked "Dictation file", Jan. 8, 1953 to Feb. 5, 1953 (all are carbon), 51-3
      - 1955-1958, 51-4
      - 1959-Feb. 1963, 51-5
      - 1965-1971, 51-6
    - Aerospace Historian, Ramsey Potts, Editor 1965-1969, 51-7
    - Air Education Foundation 1958, 51-8
    - Air Force (magazine): Correspondence 1955-1965, 51-9 to 51-13
      Also includes correspondence with Space Digest (magazine). Both magazines published by Air Force Association. Large amount of correspondence with John F. Loosbrock, the chief editor of both publications. 1 item 1950.
    - Air Force Academy
      See AIR FORCE: United States Air Force Academy
    - Air Force Association 1955-1961, 1969, 51-14 to 51-15
      - Marked "Policy Committee", 51-14
      - Marked "National", 51-15
        WBL was a member of the Air Power Policy Committee of the AFA.
    - B-70 Files
      See AIR FORCE: RS-70 Files
    - B-36 Investigation, 51-16 to 51-17
      - 1949: Material on investigation, 51-16
      - 1955: "B-36 Investigation Five Years After", 51-17
    - B-36: Policy Statement (to meet Gallery and other attacks) 1949, 52-1
      D.V. Gallery is a Rear Admiral in the United States Navy.
    - Baldwin, Hanson W. 1951, 52-2
      See also AIR FORCE: B-36 Investigation
    - Bong Air Force Base
      See AIR FORCE: Richard I. Bong Air Force Base
    - Brown, Harold (Secretary of the Air Force) 1965, 52-3
    - Cabell (General) 1960, 52-4
    - Cameron, Robert A.
      See AIR FORCE: Canadian Joint Staff
    - Canadian Joint Staff 1961, 52-5
      Correspondence with Air Commodore Robert A. Cameron.
    - Conant, James Bryant 1947-1953, 52-6
    - Coolidge, Charles A. (Hon.) 1958, 52-7
    - Devan, S. Arthur
      See AIR FORCE: U.S. Library of Congress, Legislative Reference Service
    - Division of Responsibility for Deciding Military Policy Issues 1949-1950, 52-8
    - Documents Relating to Genesis of 143-wing Air Force 1951-1956, 52-9
      Includes large amount of correspondence between WBL and U.S. Senator Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr.
    - Donnelly, H.C. ("Sam") 1957-1960, 52-10
      Includes material on missile investigation, 1957 (Senator Johnson).
    - Douglas, James H., Jr.1955-1962, 52-11 to 52-14
      Douglas became Undersecretary of the Air Force in 1953 and Secretary of the Air Force in 1957.
    - Evaluations in WSEG 1946-1950, 52-15
    - Finletter, Thomas K.1949-1954, 52-16
    - Flags and flagstaffs 1955, 52-17
    - General Electric, Defense Evaluation Operation, 52-18
      Folder contains pamphlet "Notes on Signigicant Trends in the Military Situation, January 15, 1959" by General Hansell.
    - Great Britain, Minister of Defense: Statements and memoranda relating to defense and to the effectiveness of the RAF in World War II 1948, 52-19
    - Green, Murray 1954-1971, 52-20 to 52-22
    - Judge Advocate General's School: Advanced Degree Bill 1962, 1963, 53-1 to 53-2
      - Correspondence, 53-1
      - Printed materials, 53-2
    - Kissinger, Henry A., Nuclear Weapons and Foreign Policy 1957, 53-3
      Reviews, summary, etc.
    - Krock, Arthur 1949-1954, 53-4
    - Kuter, Laurence S. (General) 1948-1961, 53-5
    - Leach, Walter Barton; Consultant Work for Dept. of Air Force 1946-1966, 53-6 to 53-13
      - Appointments and orders, 53-6
      - Correspondence 1956-1963, 53-7 to 53-9
      - General policy papers by WBL, 53-10
      - Transportation requests and travel vouchers, 1964-1966, 53-11
      - Consultant work, 1946-1947; includes some work done for War Department, 53-12
      - Personal information re financial matters, etc., 1962-1965, 53-13
    - Leach, Walter Barton, Equipment issued (personal) 1942-1950, 53-14
    - Leach, Walter Barton, European trip, September 1956: Correspondence re travel arrangements, 53-15
    - Leach, Walter Barton, London trip, October 1942, January 1943: Memoranda, 53-16
    - Leach, Walter Barton, Memoranda as Consultant to the USAF with introductory material by WBL and John Booth 1949-1956, 53-17 to 54-5
      - Memorandum... re USAF relationship to Air Force magazine,November 8, 1949, 53-17
      - John Booth, 53-18
      - Introduction-Role of Consultant, 53-19
      - Right Man for Right Job, 53-20
      - Public Information, 53-21
      - Negotiation and Interservice Relations, 54-1
      - Congressional Relations, 54-2
      - Secretary of Defense, 54-3
      - Process of Decision, 54-4
      - Miscellaneous, 54-5
    - Leach, Walter Barton, Memorandum for the Record Re USAF Safe in WBL's Custody 1963, 54-6
    - Leach, Walter Barton, Mission to London: Reports and memoranda, June-July 1948, 54-7
    - Leach, Walter Barton: 1942 Miscellany; 8th Air Force; Spaatz, 54-8
    - Leach, Walter Barton: OSAF File 1942-1955, 54-9
    - Leach Walter Barton. Official records, retirement papers, reserve status 1946, 54-10
    - Leach, Walter Barton: Personal military file; travel orders 1943-1949, 54-11 to 54-12
    - Leach, Walter Barton. Poem: " Inchon and Off", n.d., 54-13
    - LeMay, Curtis E. (General) 1956-1970, 54-14 to 54-15
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr. (U.S. Senator) 1947-1953, 54-16
      See also AIR FORCE: Documents Relating to Genesis of 143-wing Air Force
    - Loosbrock, John F.
      See AIR FORCE: Air Force (magazine)
    - MacArthur, Douglas 1941, 54-17
    - McConnell, J.P. (General, Vice Chief of Staff) 1967-1968, 54-18
    - McDermott, Robert F. (Colonel) 1959-1964, 54-19 to 54-20
    - MacIntyre, Malcolm A. 1957-1959, 55-1
    - MAINBRACE
      See AIR FORCE: Operation MAINBRACE
    - Martin, Glen W. (Brigadier General) 1949-1971, 55-2 to 55-4
    - Meyers v. United States 1946-1948, 55-5
    - Musgrave Task Force 1956, 55-6
    - Negotiation Techniques 1946-1949, 1952, 1956, 55-7 to 55-11
      WBL delivered several lectures on negotiation techniques at the Air University, Air War College and Air Command and Staff School, Maxwell Field, Alabama, in 1947 and 1948.
    - Norstad, Lauris (General, USAF) 1947-1970, 55-12 to 55-13
      See also AIR FORCE: Unification
    - North American Air Defense Command-Symposium, Air Force Academy, April 20-22, 1960., 55-14
      Symposium was held during the Spring meeting of the Scientific Advisory Board.
    - 143-Wing Air Force
      See AIR FORCE: Documents Relating to Genesis of 143-wing Air Force
    - Operation MAINBRACE n.d., 55-15
    - Operations Analysis, Department of the Air Force 1958-1966, 55-16 to 56-1
      - General matters; correspondence with chiefs of OA Zimmerman, Hower, Calafato, Brothers, 55-16
      - OA Conference, Orlando, Florida, October 4, 5, 1962, 56-1
    - Operations Analysis History Booklet 1950, 56-2
    - Operations Analysis Section, AAF 1944, 1946, 56-3 to 56-4
    - Paul, Leo Francis (Colonel) 1954-1957, 56-5
      Killed in airplane crash in October 1957, Folder includes memorials.
    - Phillips, Cabell: re AFA 1959, 56-6
    - Posvar, Wesley W. (Colonel) 1961-1968, 56-7
    - Power, Thomas S. (General) 1959, 1960, 56-8
      Includes material relating to arrangements during General Power's visit and lecture to Defense Policy Seminar, March 9, 1960.
    - Quarles, Donald A. 1955-1958, 56-9
      Quarles was Secretary of the Air Force.
    - RS-70 Files 1961-1963, 56-10 to 56-16
      - I: General materials, 1961-1962, 56-10 to 56-13
      - II: North American Aviation, 1961-1963, 56-14
      - III: Reports (Dept. of Defense), Armed Services Committee, etc., 1962, 56-15
      - Miscellaneous items, 1962, 56-16
    - Reorganization of the Department of Defense, 56-17 to 57-5
      - -1958 Reorganization Act: Material, 56-17 to 56-19
      - -Miscellaneous material, 1958: I, 57-1 to 57-2
      - -Miscellaneous material, 1958: II, 57-3 to 57-5
    - Richard I. Bong Air Force Base 1960, 57-6
    - Richardson, Robert C., III (Brigadier General), 57-7 to 57-8
    - 70 Group Air Force, 1948: Gallery report, 57-9
    - Sharp, Dudley C. (Secretary of the Air Force) 1959, 1960, 57-10
    - Slessor, Sir John 1952-1955, 57-11
    - Smith, Frederick H., Jr. 1948-1961, 57-12
    - Spaatz, Carl A. (General) 1948-1951, 57-13
    - Space Digest (magazine)
    - Space Education Foundation 1959, 57-14
    - Story, Charles Dale
    - Sykes, Ethelred L. 1949-1952, 57-15
    - Symington, Stuart 1949-1955, 58-1 to 58-4
      58-4 contains photographs of various functions honoring Symington's "farewell".
    - Techniques of Negotiation
      See AIR FORCE: Negotiation Techniques
    - Trenchard: "Air Power" 1945, 1946, 58-5
    - Twining, Nathan B. (General) 1956, 1958, 58-6
    - Unification 1948-1960, 58-7 to 58-15
      - Unification technique of deciding major issues 1948-1950, 58-8
      - Unification Project: Air Force Staff Group 1956-1957, 58-9
      - Materials: 1956-1960, 58-10 to 58-12
      - WBL Defense Policy Seminar lecture, November 18, 1959 (with Bob Berry), 58-13 to 58-14
      - Memorandum to Mr. Finletter on the subject " The 'Task' Concept in Planning Forces in Being", 1950; also letter to Lt. General Norstad, 1949, 58-15
    - United States Air Force Academy, Colorado: I 1957-1964, 58-16
    - United States Air Force Academy, Colorado: II 1956-1965, 58-17
    - United States Air Force Academy, Colorado: Problems Other Than Advanced Degrees 1962, 59-1 to 59-2
      "Report of the U.S. Air Force Academy, Academic Advisory Committee, 1962: Information on the AFA prepared for Professor W. Barton Leach".
    - United States Air Force: Students 1946-1951, 59-3 to 59-4
    - U.S. Department of the Air Force: selected articles re tactical air operations in Korean War. July-Aug. 1950, 50-5 to 59-6
    - U.S. Library of Congress, Legislative Reference Service. Re Public Affairs Bulletin No. 75, " Planning National Defense, 1950-1970" by S. Arthur Devan., 59-7
    - U.S. War Department, Army Air Forces, Committee of Operations Analysis
      See end of this SERIES
    - U.S. War Department, Army Air Forces: Misecellany 1942-1945 (chronological file), 59-8 to 59-13
      Files were marked "de-classified" by U.S. Air Force in 1973. Files consist of orders, memoranda, routing sheets, correspondence, etc.; they have been arranged chronologically.
      - 1942, 59-8 to 59-10
      - 1943, 59-11
      - 1944, 59-12
      - 1945, 59-13
    - Vandenberg, Hoyt S. (General USAF) 1949-1954, 60-1
    - Vinson Committee Report 1950, 60-2
    - Wiley, Richard A. 1951, 1952, 60-3
    - Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, 60-4
      Correspondence re lecture WBL delivered April 14, 15, 1960 which he called "Policy Problems at the Air Force Secretary Level".
    - Zuckert, Eugene M. 1947-1964, 60-5
    - U.S. War Department, Army Air Forces, Committee of Operations Analysis, 60-6
      1 bound item December 1942 to November 1944
      WBL member of Committee. Volume consists of memoranda on U.S. war effort and state of enemy war production and enemy defense installations and efforts.
- CONTINGENT II
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE (UNBOUND)
    - Bermuda 1962, 61-1
    - The Boston Herald 1950 - 1958, 61-2
    - Christian Science Monitor 1955 - 1961, 61-3
    - Combs, Cecil E. (Brig. General) 1955 - 1960, 61-4
    - Dupuy, Trevor N. 1961, 61-5
    - Emme, Eugene M. 1954 - 1960, 61-6
    - Hardee, W. Covington 1958 - 1959, 61-7
    - Hoag, Alden 1951 - 1960, 61-8
      Mr. Hoag was chief editorial writer for The Boston Herald.
    - Moran, Joseph H., 2nd. 1959, 61-9
    - Newbury, Jerry 1957 - 1958, 61-10
    - Persons, Wilton B. (Major General) 1955 - 1959, 61-11
    - Sylvania Electronic Systems 1959 - 1960, 61-12 to 61-13
      File contains several pamphlets regarding the capabilities of Sylvania electronic equipment and regarding other companies' defense industries divisions.
    - Tudor, Owen 1957 - 1962, 61-14
    - A, B, C - Miscellany, 61-15 to 61-16
      - 16-15, Adams, Warren S. 2nd. 1958 Anderson, Robert B. 1957 Andrews, Fletcher R. 1961 Army-Navy-Air Force Register and Defense Times 1959 Bill, Albert S., Jr. 1960 Binkley, John T. 1959 - 1960 Boshkoff, Douglas 1960 Bregy, Philip A. 1962 Cabell, C.P. (General) 1962 Cain, Mrs. Robert. 1961 Bar Exam.1963 Cantrall, Arch M. 1961 Cary, Russell S. 1960 Casner, Truman S. 1958 Cass, Leo J. 1963 Chadwick, G.S., Jr. 1962 Chapman, Brainerd 1961 Chapman, James W. 1960 - 1961
      - 16-16, Cherington, Paul W. 1960 Colby College 1961 Collins, Theodore J. 1962 Conlon, Joseph T., Jr. 1962 The Consad Corporation 1962 Cooley, Thomas M. II 1960 Coolidge, William A. 1960 The Cornell Law School 1961 Cotter, Richard J., Jr. 1956 Counihan, Paul G. 1955 Covington, John R. 1962 Crane, Robert D. 1959 - 1960 Cronin, Mrs. Jeremiah 1961 Crooks, Thomas E. 1963 Currie, Brainerd 1960
    - D - H - Miscellany, 61-17 to 61-18
      - 61-17, Dickinson School of Law 1959 - 1961 Division of Immigration and Americanization 1961 Dixon, James A. 1959 The Economist 1959 Edmondson, Mrs. D'Arcy 1960 Everest, Frank F. 1961 Farr, Warren F. 1960 Fine, Joseph 1962 Finley, John H., Jr. 1960 Finnigan, Patrick J. 1955 Fitzgerald, Neal 1960 Fitzgibbons, Harold E., Jr. 1960 Fong, Hiram L. 1961 Ford, Gerald R., Jr. 1958 Fordyce, C. Powell 1959 - 1961
      - 61-18, Frank, Anita 1958 Fuller, Lon L. 1959 The General Electric Defense Quarterly 1960 Golden, Max 1962 Gravel, Clarke A. 1961 Gillen, Mrs. D.V. 1962 Graves, Paul D. 1958 Gray, Leslie B. 1960 Gulliver, Ashbel G. 1959 Haley, Whitney 1958 Hammonds, Oliver W. 1958 Hanlon, R. Timothy 1961 Harris, Roger 1961 Haskins, George L. 1958 Hastings, Robert P. 1961 Haves, Robert 1963 Haynes, Tonda 1958 Hickok, Leila 1959 Hornstein, Harriet 1959 Hovey, Scott W. 1962 Howard, Michael 1958 Howe, Mark deWolfe 1959 Hunt, Mrs. Albert B. 1960 Hurley, Francis X. 1960 - 1963 Hyman, Phillip 1959
  - DEFENSE STUDIES
    - American Journal of National Defense, 1955 - 1960, 62-1
      File relates to publication which was never actually started.
    - Anderson, Robert B. (Deputy Secretary of Defense) 1955 - 1957, 62-2
    - Burgess, Carter L. (Assistant Secretary of Defense) 1954 - 1956, 62-3
    - Center for International Affairs (Harvard University) 1958, 62-4
    - Dartmouth College 1959 - 1963, 62-5
    - Defense Policy Seminar 1956 - 1957, 62-6
      Miscellaneous memoranda
    - Defense Policy Seminar Lecture, December 3, 1958, 62-7
      Memorandum on file contains WBL's Memorandum on the lecture by General Philips
    - Defense Policy Seminar 1958 - 1959, 62-8
    - Defense Policy Seminar 1959 - 1960, 62-9
    - Defense Policy Seminar 1960 - 1961, 62-10
    - Defense Policy Seminar, 62-11
      Miscellaneous
    - Department of Defense - Miscellany, 62-12
      Mottley, Charles M. 1956
      Schooley, C. Herschel 1954
      Seaton, Frederick A. 1954
      Stanley, Timothy W. 1955
    - DuFlon, Henry A. (Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense, Manpower and Personnel) 1955 - 1956, 62-13
    - Dupuy, Trevor N. 1955 - 1964, 62-14
      - Correspondence 1955 - 1956, 62-14 to 62-16
      - Institute for Defense Analysis (Interim Council on Security and Defense) 1959 - 1962, 62-17
      - Historical Evaluation and Research Organization (H.E.R.O) 1962 - 1964, 62-18 to 63-1
      - Miscellaneous, 63-2
    - Financing 1954 - 1955, 63-3
    - Finletter, Thomas K. 1954 - 1958, 63-4 to 63-5
      On March 29, 1955, Mr. Finletter lectured to the D.P.S. File contains a copy of WBL's introduction; also, a photograph of that meeting of the seminar.
    - The Ford Foundation 1954 - 1958, 63-6 to 63-7
      File contains mostly correspondence
    - George Washington University 1958 - 1960, 63-8
    - Harvard Radcliffe Committee for Nuclear Weapons Development 1960, 63-9
    - History 138b, 1956 - 1957, 63-10 to 63-12
    - Imperial Defence College (London, England) 1957, 63-13
    - Industrial College of the Armed Forces 1957, 63-14
    - International Academy of Law and Science 1964 - 1967, 63-15 to 63-16
      File relates to WBL's membership in the Academy and to the speech he made to its Third Annual Meeting, London, July 19, 1965: "Meeting Ground of Law and Science in War: Operations Analysis in U.S.A.A.F., 1942 - 1954"
      - Correspondence, 1964 - 1967, 63-15
      - Miscellaneous including a copy of speech, 63-16
    - Jackson Committee 1959, 63-17
    - Kelley, William A. 1961 - 1967, 64-1
    - Kingston - McClughry, E.J. (Air Vice Marshall, Royal Air Force) 1956 - 1957, 64-2
    - Kissinger Lecture, Commentary on, 64-3
      File contains WBL's "Commentary" on the D.P.S. lecture of October 1, 1958 by Henry Kissinger
    - Kistiakowsky and Whipple 1954 - 1957, 64-4
      File deals with D.P.S. meeting of February 8, 1955 at which George B. Kistiakowsky and Fred L Whipple were lecturers.
    - Laredo Air Force Base, Texas 1957, 64-5
      File relates to speech given by WBL to 3640th Pilot Training Wing graduating class at Laredo Air Force Base, February 4, 1957. File contains a draft of the speech (dated January 14, 1957) and a picture of WBL at the base.
    - Lincoln, George A. (Colonel, U.S. Army) 1956, 64-6
    - Masland, John W. (Professor of Government,; Darmouth College) 1955 - 1957, 64-7
    - Mason, Edward S. (Dean of the Graduate School of Public Administration, Harvard University) 1956 - 1957, 64-8
    - Milton Fund 1954 - 1960, 64-9
    - Ministry of Defense, London, England 1955 - 1957, 64-10
    - Naval and Marine Participation in the Defense Policy Seminar 1954 - 1956, 64-11
    - The Ohio State University 1956 - 1964, 64-12 to 64-13
      File relates to National Security Policy seminar conducted at Ohio State.
    - The Ohio State University Military History Course,1957, 64-14 to 64-16
    - Porter, Charles L. (U.S. Congressman) 1957 - 1958, 64-17
    - Potts, Ramsey D., Jr. 1955 - 1960, 64-18
    - Praeger, Frederick A. (Publisher) 1956 - 1958, 64-19
    - Public Affairs Press, 1956, 64-20
    - Quesada, Elwood R. 1959 - 1960, 65-1
      File deals with D.P.S. meeting of March 30, 1960 at which Mr. Quesada (head of the Federal Aviation Agency) participated.
    - R.O.T.C. - Air Force1954 - 1963, 65-2 to 65-3
    - R.O.T.C. - Army 1954 - 1959, 65-4
    - R.O.T.C. - Navy 1955 - 1957, 65-5
    - Rockefeller Brothers Foundation Project1957, 65-6
    - "Santagelo Amendment" 1959, 65-7
    - Smithies, Arthur 1955 - 1957, 65-8
    - Student Conference on United States Affairs1955, 65-9
      Conference was held at the United States Military Academy, West Point, November 30 - December 3, 1955.
    - Tedder - The Lord Tedder, G.C.B. (Marshall of the Royal Air Force) 1955, 65-10
    - Textbook, 65-11
    - United States Military Academy 1959 - 1962, 65-12
    - University of California, Los Angeles 1959, 65-13
      File relates to the possible establishment of a defense policy seminar at U.C.L.A.
    - University of Wisconsin Law School 1955 - 1961, 65-14
    - White, H. Lee 1957 - 1958, 65-15
    - World Affairs Council 1957 - 1958, 65-16
    - Miscellaneous (chronological) 1955 - 1963, 65-17
  - HARVARD MISCELLANY
    - Griswold, Erwin N. (Dean,; Harvard Law School) 1954 - 1963, 66-1
    - Harvard Alumni Bulletin 1958, 66-2
    - Harvard Business Review 1958, 66-3
    - Harvard Law Review 1959 - 1964, 66-4
    - Harvard Law School: General Correspondence (chronological) 1959 - 1963, 66-5
    - Harvard Law School: Institute of International Legal Studies 1947 - 1954, 66-6